okay right now I'm going to go over the
band external rotation this is a really
tricky exercise and uh it's not it'll
you'll feel it in your obliques but it's
not an abdominal exercise so much as a
glute exercise specifically the upper
glutes to help teach you how to use your
glutes for exploding when you when you
twist in sports um for example when you
swing a bat or swing a racket or you
know throw something to the side so the
setup is pretty tricky if I were to set
up like this and then when I rotate it
there'd be no tension here so you can't
position yourself perpendicular to the
load you have to kind of angle your body
this way a little bit so now I have the
band coming this way now when I twist
there'll still be a lot of tension on
the glute so
um when when I twist to the the right
I'm going to feel it in my left glue
when I twist to the left I'm going to
feel it in my right glue so um and when
you get good at this you can really
really feel a lot of tension in the glue
so I put my arm straight ahead and I'm
twisting this uh my my left leg I'm
going to rotate
externally and while holding the band
straight out
so
[Music]
you won't really feel it a lot till you
get to a little bit higher reps like
eight or 10 and then you'll feel it burn
like crazy so now if I switch to the
other
side um got to get your body in the
right position and
[Music]
then you're using your upper
glutes to perform that motion